Guide to the Walter Weir Papers, 1909-1996 and undated, bulk 1950-1990 RL.01362
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches Series, circa 1928-1994 and undated, 7 boxes
  Includes published and unpublished writings by Weir both for advertising industry audiences and the general public. There is also correspondence with Weir's writing agent, Florence Crowthers, Rance Crain of Crain Communications, and transcripts of talks Weir gave at various advertising industry meetings throughout his career. Arranged into three subseries--Advertising Writings; Other Writings; and Speeches--and chronologically therein.
  - Advertising Writings, 1935-1994 and undated
    Consists of published and unpublished writings about advertising, including autobiographical manuscripts about Weir's career as well as other advertising-industry related projects. For transcripts of speeches, see Speeches subseries. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1935-1937, Printer's Ink columns (Box 13)
    - Circa 1941, Text for How to get a job and win success in advertising, by Walter A. Lowen (Box 13)
    - 1942, Get Fighting Mad (Box 13)
    - 1958, Creative insight piece in Advertising Age (Box 13)
    - 1960, Excerpt from On The Writing of Advertising (Box 13)
    - 1963, Truth in Advertising and other Heresies, Chapter 6 (Box 13)
    - 1970-1973, U.H.T. Milk (Box 13)
    - Circa 1970, Chapter 1: Wayburn, Rio Rita, Kessler, Dowling (Box 13)
    - Circa 1970, On Mad, Mad, Madison Avenue, Typescript of Book 1, Ayer (1928-1935), 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Circa 1970, On Mad, Mad, Madison Avenue, Typescript of Book 2, Fletcher & Ellis (1937-1938) (Box 13)
    - 1973-1993, Correspondence (Box 13)
    - 1977, Is Business Correspondence a Bothersome Chore? Beware (Box 13)
    - 1977, Datsun piece in Advertising Age (Box 13)
    - 1977-1994, Correspondence with Crain Communications, Inc. (Box 13)
    - 1980, Madison Avenue Magazine project (Box 13)
    - 1980, Reversion of rights documents for Truth in Advertising and Other Heresies and On the Writing of Advertising (Box 13)
    - 1984 Oct. 15, Another Look at Subliminal 'Facts', Advertising Age (Box 13)
    - 1984, Copyright certificate for Guide to Interest-evoking, sales-inducing, non-irritating, Advertising (Box 13)
    - Circa 1984, Making Advertising More Acceptable Through Better Written Ads (Box 13)
    - 1986, Trial article for TV Guide (Box 13)
    - Circa 1992, Integrated Marketing, Databasing Rehashes of Already Established Activities (Box 13)
    - 1993, How to Create Interest-Evoking, Sales-Inducing, Non-Irritating Advertising (Box 14)
    - 1993, Royalty reports from University Microfilms, Inc. (Box 14)
    - 1994, Royalty reports from The Haworth Press for How to Create... (Box 14)
    - Undated, Ad Man manuscript (Box 14)
    - Undated, Brown & Tarcher (1935-1937) (Box 14)
    - Undated, Brown & Weir (1945-1946) (Box 14)
    - Undated, Different manuscript entitled On Mad, Mad, Madison Avenue, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Undated, Follow the Simple Directions (Box 14)
    - Undated, J.M.Mathes (1938-1941), 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Undated, Loose pages from autobiographical manuscripts, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Undated, Lord & Thomas, Kenyon & Eckhardt, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Undated, The Ad Game (Box 15)
    - Undated, Through the Looking Glass (Box 15)
    - Undated, Walter Weir, Inc. (Box 15)
    - Undated, You and Advertising radio transcripts (Box 15)
  - Other Writings, circa 1928-1994 and undated
    Includes correspondence with editors and literary agents, as well as clippings, drafts, and published copies of poetry, prose, and newspaper columns written by Weir, which do not directly relate to his career in advertising. Arranged chronologically.
    - Circa 1928, Cross Bearings: being excerpts, with cross references, from three years of reading, 6 folders (Box 15)
    - 1932 and undated, Maypole, and other autobiographical writing, 4 folders (Box 16)
      Pages from different manuscripts appear mixed. No way to discern original order with accuracy.
    - 1937, For Fathers Only (Box 16)
    - 1938-1995 and undated, Correspondence with various editors (Box 16)
    - 1941, The Bed by the Window (Box 16)
    - 1943, Will Basic English Make the Grade in Advertising? (Box 16)
    - 1945-1956, Correspondence with Russell & Volkening, Inc. Literary Agents (Box 16)
    - 1945, Plenty On The Ball (Box 16)
    - 1945, She Brought it on Herself (Box 16)
    - Circa 1945, Grateful Heart (Box 16)
    - Circa 1945, If You Can't Be True (Box 16)
    - Circa 1945, Music Hath Charms (Box 16)
    - Circa 1945, The Bathroom Scales (Box 16)
    - Circa 1945, Turn Backward (Box 16)
    - 1946, Easy Come (Box 16)
    - 1946, Henry and the Hop-A-Copter (Box 16)
    - 1946, Muscles by Mail (Box 16)
    - 1946, Only One to Win (Box 16)
    - 1946, Out-Of-Town Visitor (Box 16)
    - 1946, Premonition (Box 16)
    - 1946, R.A. Loves P.B. (Box 16)
    - 1946, Stand-In (Box 16)
    - 1946, The Old Man (Box 16)
    - 1947, Follow The Leader (Box 16)
    - 1947, Little Things That Make History (Box 16)
    - 1947 and 1967, Permissions and royalties (Box 16)
    - 1947, Special Delivery (Box 16)
    - 1947, The Other Woman (Box 16)
    - 1947, Why I've Taught My Children To Be Selfish (Box 17)
    - 1948, A Matter of Understanding (Box 17)
    - 1948, A Sucker For Advertising (Box 17)
    - 1948, Mrs. Lefevre (Box 17)
    - 1948, Pale Hands I Loved (Box 17)
    - 1948, The Decision (Box 17)
    - 1948 and undated, Typed poems of famous poets (Box 17)
    - 1949, Happily Ever After (Box 17)
    - 1949, Honor Thy Father (Box 17)
    - 1949, How To Live with Seven Children --And Like It (Box 17)
    - 1949-1950, Knife In The Heart, 2 folders (Box 17)
      Contains a substantial amount of readership response to the publication of this article about Weir's daughter Karyn, who was diagnosed with patent ductus arteriosis.
    - 1950, Ella Jean And The Psychiatrist (Box 17)
    - 1950 Jan 11, How to deal with the Russians, a talk given to the Langhorne Lions (Box 17)
    - 1950, How Wise Is A Woman? (Box 17)
    - 1950, New York Adventure (Box 17)
    - 1950, On Schedule (Box 17)
    - 1950, The Real Meaning Of Korea (Box 17)
    - 1950, You, Too, Can Be A Yachtsman (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, A Little Fatherly Advice (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, Even If It Kills You...Be A Pal With Your Children (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, How I Predict My Children's Behavior (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, Johnny-Come-Lately (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, Mrs. Gamelin (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, Murderer Aboard (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, Number 29, Infants Wear (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, The Man from the U.N. (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, The Neglected Front In The Anti-Discrimination Battle (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, The Visitor (Box 17)
    - Circa 1950, Can American Women Stop a Third World War? Write A Letter to Stalin Today (Box 17)
    - 1951, End of the Road (Box 17)
    - 1951, Repeat Performance (Box 17)
    - 1951, The Plaque (Box 17)
    - 1951, Tourist Attraction (Box 17)
    - 1954, My Willie Can Do Anything (Box 17)
    - 1954, The Line's Busy (Box 17)
    - 1954, Waves, a poem published in This Week Magazine (Box 17)
    - 1955, Next Christmas Is Going To Be Different! (Box 17)
    - Circa 1955, All I Want Is Service! (Box 17)
    - Circa 1955, Don' Stop De Carnival! (Box 17)
    - 1956, The Puzzle (Box 17)
    - 1957, The Executive Function (Box 17)
    - 1960, Meager Music (Box 17)
    - 1960 and undated, So Long as Other Lovers, typescript (Box 18)
    - 1961, The Midnight Clear, a short story published in McCall's (Box 18)
    - 1963, Black Oranges, a poem published in McCall's (Box 18)
    - 1966, In Praise of the Small Breasted Woman (Box 18)
    - 1966, 1970-1973, and undated, Rum book (Box 18)
    - Circa 1966, How to Enjoy Champagne for What it is and Life in the Haute Savoie (Box 18)
    - Circa 1970-1990, Loose poems and prose (Box 18)
    - 1974-1976, Correspondence with Florence Crowther, author's agent (Box 18)
    - 1975-1981, Correspondence with editors of Ladies Home Journal (Box 18)
    - 1978, Why--And How--To Use a Real Estate Broker When You Sell Your Home (Box 18)
    - 1980, Presidential Race 1980, New York Magazine submissions (Box 18)
    - 1980, The Russian People and U.S. Wheat (Box 18)
    - 1985, Are We Promoting Hostage-Taking? (Box 18)
    - 1989-1991, If I were George Bush, and other columns for the Courier Times, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - 1994, Clinton's Blunder Can Extend Human Rights in China (Box 18)
    - Undated, A Tribute to Marshall Wolper (Box 18)
    - Undated, Henry and the Unicopter: A proposed series of television programs for children based on an idea developed in a short story which appeared originally in the Saturday Evening Post. Originally published in 1946. (Box 18)
    - Undated, So Once Was I: An Autobiography (Box 18)
    - Undated, The Paths I Chose (Box 18)
  - Speeches, 1940-1993 and undated
    Contains complete and incomplete transcripts of talks and addresses that Weir composed and delivered throughout his career in advertising. Some are accompanied by correspondence and clippings. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1940-1949, Incomplete transcripts (Box 18)
    - 1943 May 27, Publishers' Weekly Dinner (Box 18)
    - 1944 July 8, Will Basic English Make the Grade in Advertising (Box 18)
    - Circa 1945, Friends' Meeting House, Newtown PA (Box 18)
    - 1946 June 7, Brown Preparatory School (Box 18)
    - 1948 Sept. 13, Tea Advertising Today, Tea Association (Box 18)
    - 1948 Dec. 2, EIA (Box 18)
    - 1949 Apr. 27, Friends' Meeting House, Langhorne (Box 18)
    - 1950-1959, Incomplete transcripts (Box 18)
    - Circa 1950, The Loose Nut at the Wheel, Advertising Federation of America (Box 18)
    - 1954 May 7, Content: Heart of the Message (Box 18)
    - 1955 Nov. 15, National Ass'n of Bedding Mnfrs. (Box 18)
    - 1956 June 13, The Importance of Copy in Closing the Sale, Harvard Business School (Box 19)
    - 1956 Aug. 20, The Shoe on the Other Foot, Nat. Shoe Mfgrs. Assoc. (Box 19)
    - 1957 Oct. 17, On Vance Packard's The Hidden Persuaders, American Marketing Association (Box 19)
    - 1959 Mar. 6, Total Advertising, Detroit Adcrafter's Club (Box 19)
    - 1959 Aug. 11, Talk to Mill Street Business Men's Association (Box 19)
    - 1960-1969, Incomplete transcripts (Box 19)
    - 1960 Sept. 8, The Problem of Restraint in a Free Society, ABC Cleveland Ad Club Talk (Box 19)
    - 1960 Nov. 2, The Image of the Presidency, Saybrooke College (Box 19)
    - 1960 Nov. 28, On the Writing of Advertising, Advertising & Selling Course (Box 19)
    - 1961 Feb 8, 4 A's Michigan Chapter (Box 19)
    - 1962 Oct. 15, The Client-Agency Relationship (Box 19)
    - Circa 1975, Advertising and Press Freedom (Box 19)
      [Removed to Oversize Materials, Box 20
    - 1979 Nov. 8, Talk--UT (Box 19)
    - 1979, The Big One That Got Away, UT-AFF Ad Club (Box 19)
    - 1984 May 16, Marketing Excellence Awards Dinner (Box 19)
    - 1984 Sept. 10, Beecham Talk, Vail Colorado (Box 19)
    - 1987, James Webb Young Fund Address (Box 19)
    - 1993 Oct. 28, The Big Opporrtunity for the Small Agency, Mariah group, Second Wind Ltd., Scottsdale, AR (Box 19)
    - Undated, untitled (Box 19)
- Oversize Materials, 2 Boxes
  - Musical Series
    - The Hucksters
      - Musical score, undated, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Other Music
      - Australia Trip, 1962 (Box 20)
      - Little Cowboy Boots, 1955 (Box 20)
      - Puerto Rico, USA, undated (Box 20)
      - Somewhere out in the morning, 1995 and undated (Box 20)
      - The Bulletin Song, undated (Box 20)
      - White Man, undated (Box 20)
  - Professional Series
    - La Borie/Weir
      - Interhydro AG correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 21)
      - Interhydro AG vs. Ralston Purina, et. al., 1977 (Box 21)
      - Legal agreement between Interhydro AG and Ralston Purina Company, 1977 (Box 21)
      - Luwasa System, 1973-1985, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Stratford of Texas and Green Thumb Corp. restraining order and injunction, 1974 (Box 21)
    - Other Materials
      - Starch Readership Report, 1986 (Box 21)
  - Writings and Speeches
    - Advertising Writings
      - 1958, Creative insight piece in Advertising Age (Box 21)
    - Other Writings
      - 1954, Waves, a poem published in This Week Magazine (Box 21)
      - 1961, The Midnight Clear, a short story published in McCall's (Box 21)
      - 1963, Black Oranges, a poem published in McCall's (Box 21)
      - 1966, 1970-1973, and undated, Rum book (Box 21)
    - Speeches
      - Circa 1975, Advertising and Press Freedom (Box 21)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1 box
  Includes audiocassettes and audiotapes of radio spots and other advertising-related recordings. Originals are closed to researchers. Use Copies must be made before researchers can access this material.
  - Originals (CLOSED TO RESEARCHERS)
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Audiocassettes
      Note: Use copies can usually be made on demand by Research Services staff.
      - OR1-OR10. Account Management, 1982 and undated, TRT=C60 each. (Box 22)
      - OR11. ASAE George Ferris, The Million Dollar Round Table Tape Cassette Program, 1981, TRT=C60 (Box 22)
      - OR12. Chunky Soup, John Dodd, 1981, Feb. 5, TRT=120:00 (Box 22)
      - OR13. Demo, World Class Productions, 1986, TRT=C60 (Box 22)
      - OR14. Dramatics and Semantic of the Sale Raymond F. Triplett, CLU, The Million Dollar Round Table Tape Cassette Program, undated, TRT=C60 (Box 22)
      - OR15. FCB Radio, Levi's--Brothers, U.S. Forest--Pshtigo, Winchell's--Word Association, Eddie Bauer--21, 1980-1981, TRT=C60 (Box 22)
      - OR16. Impersonations and Straight Voice Overs, Joe Conklin, Temple University, circa 1980, TRT=C60 (Box 22)
      - OR17 MRC Presentation, MDRT Advertising Program, William T. O'Donnell, The Million Dollar Round Table Tape Cassette Program, circa 1981, TRT=10:06 (Box 22)
      - OR18. Radio spots sampler, World Class Productions, circa 1980, TRT=15:00 (Box 22)
      - OR19. Sammy Cahn, undated, TRT=C60 (Box 22)
    - Audiotapes
      NOTE: Use copies must be requested in advance.
      - OR20. E.F. Hutton, Sy Shaffer Enterprises, 1968, Sept. 12, Format: .25 inch 600 ft./1.5 mil acetate, TRT=15:00 (Box 22)
      - OR21. Jersey Tech addresses, circa 1960, Format: .25 inch 600 ft./1.5 mil acetate, TRT=15:00 (Box 22)
      - OR22. Jersey Tech tribute to W.B. Okie: Address by Dr. Weir, 1940, 1960, Format: .25 inch 600 ft./1.5 mil acetate, TRT=15:00 (Box 22)
      - OR21. Merril, Lynch, Pierce, Fenner & Beane, West Weir & Bartel Advertising, circa 1964-1968, Format: .25 inch 900-1200 ft./1.5 mil acetate, TRT=30 min. (Box 22)
      - OR22. Mountain Dew, Moore & Yellin Associates, 1967, May 11, Format: .25 inch 600 ft./1.5 mil acetate, TRT=15:00 (Box 22)
      - OR23. Mountain Dew #2 songs, Scott-Textor Productions, circa 1956-1970, Format: .25 inch 600 ft./1.5 mil acetate, TRT=15:00 (Box 22)